Andrew Ellicott Douglass papers, 1867-1962
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series V: Personal Material (Part II), 1867-1965
  - Financial Records
    - Real Estate: Tucson City Blocks. 1917-1940 (Box 171, Folder 8)
      370 Court St (Metzgar)
    - Real Estate: Tucson City Block 83, Lot 2, 6th Ave & Pennington (Garcia-Buckley, DeConcini, Page-Meisenheimer). 1926-1938 (Box 171, Folder 9)
    - Real Estate: miscellaneous. 1913-1940 (Box 171, Folder 10)
      900 Block on E. 1st St., SW Corner
      Broadway & Country Club (J.W. Taylor)
      6th Ave and Broadway (Porter)
      Roger Road (Horton)
      Lot 42, Golden Dawn Farms (Wollard-Scott)
      Ranch on Prince Rd, near Pastime Park (Price-Gerhart)
      House & grounds on Allen Road, just off of Campbell, near Ft. Lowell (Langston-Rambach)
      Lots 1-2, NW Corner of Section 19, Township 13S (Wilkerson)
    - Investments: How to Avoid Financial Tangles, by Kenneth C. Masteller. Published by American Institute for Economic Research. 3rd edition and 16th edition. 1939, 1945 (Box 172)
    - Investments: Alineometers, Inc. 1929-1931 (Box 172, Folder 1)
    - Investments: Arizona Drug Stores. 1929 (Box 172, Folder 2)
    - Investments: Atchison, Topeka & Santa Fe Railway Co. 1940-1954 (Box 172, Folder 3)
    - Investments: Cahuenga Court Apartments (Los Angeles). 1931-1940 (Box 172, Folder 4)
    - Investments: Guaranty Trust Company of New York. 1947-1954 (Box 172, Folder 5)
    - Investments: Boston & Maine Railroad. 1935-1955 (Box 172, Folder 6)
    - Investments: Detroit Edison Co., and Southern California Edison Co. 1938-1953, 1915-1948 (Box 172, Folder 7)
    - Investments: Flagstaff Lumber Company. 1911-1919 (Box 172, Folder 8)
    - Investments: Jans Investment Company (Los Angeles). 1923-1926 (Box 172, Folder 9)
    - Investments: Peoples Finance & Thrift Company of Tucson (later Peoples Investment Corp.). 1922-1942 (Box 172, Folder 10)
    - Investments: S.W. Straus and Company. 1924-1929 (Box 172, Folder 11)
    - Investments: Straus Seamless Shoe Company. 1920-1929 (Box 172, Folder 12)
    - Investments: Tucson Tourist Hotel (El Conquistadore). 1926-1928 (Box 172, Folder 13)
    - Investments: miscellaneous. 1914-1951 (Box 172, Folder 14)
    - Investments: Bonds. 1914-1950 (Box 172, Folder 15)
    - Investments: Dow Jones Averages. September 1945-March 1946 (Box 172, Folder 16)
    - Taxes: Income Tax (federal). 1917-1949 (Box 173, Folder 1-2)
    - Taxes: Income Tax (state). 1933-1944 (Box 173, Folder 3)
    - Taxes: State and County Taxes (Coconino County). 1900-1937 (Box 173, Folder 4)
    - Taxes: State and County Taxes (Pima County). 1913-1940 (Box 173, Folder 5)
    - Taxes: Assessments for Street Improvements (Tucson). 1922-1941 (Box 173, Folder 6)
    - Personal Bills. 1908-1954 (Box 174)
  - Ida (Whittington) Douglass
    - Engagement and Marriage (includes early letters, marriage liscence, clippings, list of wedding gifts, etc). August 3, 1905 (Box 175, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with A.E.D. 1905-1942 (Box 175, Folder 2-4)
    - Correspondence with University of Arizona Faculty. 1906-1946, 1965 (Box 175, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous personal material. (Box 176, Folder 1)
    - Photographs. (Box 176, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with family. 1908-1953 (Box 176, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with friends, etc. 1906-1955 (Box 176, Folder 4)
    - Teaching Materials. (Box 176, Folder 5)
  - Biography of A.E. Douglass
    - Correspondence. 1931-1939, 1954 (Box 177, Folder 1)
    - Research notes, background material. (Box 177, Folder 2)
    - A.E.D.'s personal philosophy notes as selected and copied by David Brinegar. (Box 177, Folder 3)
    - First Draft. (Box 177, Folder 4)
    - Revised Draft. (Box 177, Folder 5-7)
    - David Brinegar's "Mars Story" for Arizona Daiy Star. 1931 (Box 177, Folder 8)
  - Range Finder
    - Range Finder. (Box 178)
  - Oversize Material
    These three boxes contain oversize material on all subjects in the Collection. They have been grouped into smaller segments wherever possible. Clippings have been arrange chronologically.
    - Clippings on Tree Rings, sunspots, and weather. (Box 179)
    - "Plans for Cycloscope." 1936 (Box 179)
    - Late cycle work by A.E.D. and Bryant Bannister (charts, records, computations). 1953-1959 (Box 179)
    - Map: U.S. Geographical Surveys Weat of the 100th Meridian. Parts of central and western Arizona, Atlas sheet no. 75, New York. 1876 (Box 179)
    - Map: Republica Argentina. Red Caminera Principal. Accompanied by an "overlay" map, made by Edmund Schulman. 1946 (Box 179)
    - University of Arizona. (Box 180, Folder 1)
      Clippings:
      Inauguration of ARthur H. Wilde as President of the University ( Tucson Citizen and Arizona Daily Star, May 18, 1911)
      "Pioneers of the West," A.E.D.'s address to the Douglas High School graduating class (Douglas Paper, May 21, 1911)
      "Shall the University be Divided?" ( Tucson Citizen, September 30, 1915)
      Page from special edition of the Arizona Daiy Star, "Tucson in 1915."
      General Pershing Dedication of Memorial Fountain ( Tucson Citizen, January 31, 1920)
      University of Arizona and the "Conway Case." ( Arizona Daily Star and Tucson Citizen, October-November 1921)
      "Ex-grocer's Clerk, Now Business Man, Heads University of Arizona at Age of Thirty-Three." ( Philadelphia Evening Public Ledger, December 14, 1922)
      Series of articles on evolution by various University professors. A.E.D.'s titled, "Evolution as seen by the Astronomer." ( Tucson Citizen, December 1923-March 1924)
      "Steward Observatory Devoting Summer to Study of Mars," by Duane Hawkins ( Arizona Wildcat, August 23, 1924)
      "Roman Relics Found here Baffle Science," by Gilbert Cosuich ( Arizona Daily Star, December 13, 1925
      Anti-Evolutiuon Controversy ( Arizona Daily Star and Tucson Citizen, October 1927)
      "Dr. Douglass Announces Search for Two more Planets," by David Brinegar ( Arizona Daily Star, March 23, 1930)
      1932 Eclipse ( Arizona Daily Star, September 1, 1932
      "President H.L. Shantz's Resignation ( Arizona Wildcat, January 7, 1925)
      "Clear, Star-Studded Arizona Skies are Studied by Public at Steward Observatory," by Roger O'Mara ( Arizona Daily Star, October 15, 1950)
      "Amazing 1923 Expedition to Port Libertad is Recalled," by Dorothy Kalil ( Arizona Daily Star, May 25, 1952)
      Photographs:
      Mrs. Lavinia Steward (3 copies)
      A.E.D.'s eclipse photo at Port Libertad, Mexico
      Poster: University Lectures by A.E.D., "Big Trees and Climate of the Past," and Recent Work on Mars." (January 5-6, 1926)
    - Astronomy (general). (Box 180, Folder 2)
      Includes the folowing:
      Cippings on astronomical topics from various newspapers, including Mars, Lionids, Eclipse of 1901, Comet A 1910, "End of the Word," December 1919, Eclipse 1918, discovery of 9th planet by owell Observatory in 1930, Kitt Peak National Observatory 1958
      Drawing, "Original Observation of Solar Eclipse," March 1885
      A "Star Atlas" published by F.J.Huntington, Hartford, Conn. 1835
      Portrait
      Reproduction of painting, "Total Eclipse of the Sun, June 8, 1918"
    - Steward Observatory Blueprints. 1919-1920 (Box 180, Folder 3)
    - A.E.D.'s Family Tree. (Box 181)
    - Ellicott Family. (Box 181, Folder 1)
      Map: Plan of the City of Washington, by Andrew Ellicott, 1800
      Clippings
    - Miscellaneous clippings. (Box 181, Folder 2)
      "An Arizona Suprise, or, Malcolm Barton's Eventful Career," by Geoffrey Randolph ( The Home Treasury, July 1899)
      "Glories of Arizona," by Arthur K. Peck ( Boston Sunday Herald, August 27, 1899)
      Hassayampa Basin (photograph)
      Panorama of Flagstaff taken from tower of courthouse, 1905
      "List of Contributors to Trinity Endowment." ( Harford Weekly Times, January 6, 1910)
      "Alleged Enemy Typing up rare metals...Arizona Defense Council Adopts Resolution..." ( Tucson Citizen, May 11, 1917)
      Ad of Pima County Third iberty Loan Committee: "Budget Listing Those Who are expected to Subscribe $1000 or over." ( Tucson Citizen, April 1917?)
      Ad for the Republican Nomination of Herbert Hoover as President of the United States ( Evanston News-Index, April 29, 1920)
      "To Rainbow Bridge, One of World's Wonders. A Visit to Rainbow Bridge," by G.A. Pearson ( Los Angeles Examiner, May 22, 1927)
      "In Memoriam: Denis M. Riordan: 1848-1928." ( Coconino Sun, November 16, 1928)
      Poster regarding Del Mar Heights, "The coming Atlantic City of the Pacific Coast."
      "Hurrican Souvenir." ( The Standard-Times, New Bedford, MA, October 1, 1938)
      Round the World Fliers of 1924 ( Arizona Daily Star, September 19, 1943)
      "Trinity is Writing its own Answer to what is the Future of the Small College?" ( New Haven Register, November 26, 1950)
    - South America. (Box 181, Folder 3)
      Theatrical broadside announcing "the last show of the season" by the celebrated company of Silbon, April 12, 1891
      El Cosmos: periodico cientifico literario (Arequipa, Peru)
      La Bolsa, January 20, 1892
      "On Top of El Misti," by William E. Curtis ( Chicago Record, August 1899)
      Series of articles on South America by Frank G. Carpenter ( Los Angeles Sunday Times, 1898-1899)
      "Preliminary Map...in Bolivian Survey, 1892," by Mechelhof
      "First Aerial Survey of the Peruvian Andes by an American Expedition." ( New York Times Rotogravure picture seciton, May 1, 1932)
      Official documents from U.S. Legation in Lima giving permission to visit Peru, January 13, 1891
    - Photographs. (Box 181, Folder 4)
      7 large photographs of A.E.D.
      Astronomical Congress, World's Fair, Chicago, August 21-26, 1893
      American Astronomical Society Meetings, 1917-1919
      A.A.A.S., Southwestern Division Meetings, 1920-1932
    - Degrees and Memberships. (Box 181, Folder 5)
      Punchard Free School, Andover, MA. (Certificate of completion of course of study, June 20, 1884)
      Trinity College, Hartford, Conn. (Honorary Doctor's Degree, July 8, 1908)
      Phi Kappa Phi (certificate of election in Universit of Arizona Chapter, May 31, 1916)
      American Geographical Society (certificate of election as a fellow, April 23, 1918)
      Society of the Sons of the American Revolution (membership certificate, February 27, 1926)
      Society of Sigma Xi (certificate of membership in Arizona chapter, February 22, 1928)
      National Geographic Society (certificate of life membership, December 18, 1929)
      Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia (certificate of election as a correspondent member, May 5, 1936)
      University of Arizona (degree of Doctor of Science, June 1, 1938)
      American Philosohical Society (membership certificate, April 25, 1941)
      Masonic Certificates.
      Ida (Whittington) Douglass:
      Monrovia High School, Monrovia, Ca (Diploma, June 14, 1895)
      California State Normal School, Los Angeles, CA (Diploma, June 24, 1897)
      Radcliffe College (M.A. Degree, June 18, 1918
      Phi Kappa Phi (membership certificate, University of Arizona chapter, February 10, 1919)
      90th "Birthday Card" from Rotary Club, July 1957